uh all right so welcome to local Theory
one
uh so
I guess you have all seen the syllabus
uh if you haven't uh emailed me about
being added to the slack workspace you
should uh send me a message so I'll add
your email to the uh the stock workspace
uh where all the online communication uh
it's relevant to this course will be
will be conducted and we'll just post
you know a problem set then
you know lecture notes uh links to
videos after each lecture to the slack
workspace and also there's a channel for
questions and discussions and you should
feel free to post questions at any time
if I don't get to those questions some
other people uh the other students in
the class might might be able to to
answer and discuss with you
um uh just a few words on the
organization of this course
so
um
uh so as you know this is a graduate
course I am tasked by the department
chair to make it accessible to
experimenters so
um and so it should be it should be that
way and if you feel that you know it was
there's some things that are not uh
explained uh properly uh that's
understandable so experimented if you
complain to me and I'll try to do a
better job
um and um uh the uh there's no official
uh textbook for this course uh because
there's no book that I feel that would
be exactly aligned with the way I'd like
to introduce uh the subjects uh but uh
to uh make you uh to to give you some uh
psychological Comforts uh so you have
something to look to you can look at
weiberg evolving one which is a great
book and I will be using conventions
that are more or less going to be
consistent with weinberg's textbook note
that we have the different sign
convention uh sometimes for the
signature of the metric of the McCarthy
in space-time compared to some other
books such as
folks are more
orientate journey to particle physics
um but anyway uh on the other hand you
should know as a as gratitude students
that you should not limit yourself to
reading only a single book to be free to
to read whatever that you find is
necessary for you to understand the
material
uh so uh the the lecture notes I'll have
a handwritten actually notes I'll be
posted and we'll have a problem set once
every uh two weeks uh the plan is to
hand out the first problem set next
Thursday
uh and uh
there will be a weekly uh sections uh
that's by the TF uh Alex uh back there
and he has posted a poll on the general
channel of the slack workspace and if
you have haven't signed up you should
look at the the slot uh uh it's uh
always uh possible that we will not be
able to accommodate everybody for the
time of the section but we hope to
accomplish for most people and we can
also try to record via Zoom so that you
know make a section you can still so
look at it afterwards
um uh let's see what else ah yes uh so
there's no
um there will not be a final exam for
this course I'm not a fan of final exams
I think it's uh at least for the
graduate course it's a waste of time
both for the instructor and for the
students
um instead we will uh have uh sort of a
a final project which is more like a
slightly more sophisticated problem set
which will require a reading that goes
beyond uh the contents of the lectures
list of topics
um uh later uh during the semester
okay so let me see
is there any other organizational
issues uh are there any questions about
the general organization of the course
oh and also my office hour is uh right
after the Tuesday lectures
um uh as was in the updated syllabus by
posting on slack but um uh you should
nonetheless feel free to post questions
on slack at any time uh it's uh it's
generally better to ask questions over
slack rather than through emails because
then other people can also see the
questions and share and discuss
uh
uh what else I think uh I think that's
all I wanted to say uh any questions
okay
um
uh so
so let's get started
um
uh
what is photograph Theory
um this question is
very easy to answer
um a rough
um a rock answer would be uh but it's
basically quantum mechanics but uh
a domestic locality
um
and I've explained what that means
so in fact uh
actually a confusing uh question even
for our uh the vast majority of
businesses uh because I would say that
there are really two different uh two
conceptually slightly different things
that both are called Quantum field
Theory uh that are really conceptually
distinct
I want to discuss both in the sports
um one type of uh uh
quality theory is what I would call
local or sometimes referred to as
usually concrete
um and the other is uh what's known as a
defective
um so what are these things
um we
it's a little easier to State uh what a
note mode
qrp means
so
um this uh is a
a first of all accordingly can protect
them with uh
pump every symmetry
hundred symmetry
consists of translation uh you can save
time together with laurent's customer
uh okay so so this kind of fundability
rate first of all is upon the mechanical
system so so you know uh some uh folks
might have the applied misconception
that you might think the quantum field
Theory uh going Beyond mechanism the
generalization of quantum mechanics uh
no Quantum silver theory is not a
translation called mechanics on the
field Theory the specialization
okay so but we're going to allow our
mechanics with implementary freedom so
definitely many
uh the only requirement well not the
only requirement is One requirement on
top of the uh the kind of quantum
mechanics you learn your undergraduate
by class is that we must also have uh
contrary symmetry now
um
mechanical system
um asymmetry will be realized as the
unitary operator that icon cover space
and the operating was transformed by
conjugation with effects of the Israel
operator uh so that will also be the
case here
uh all of these uh so I'm giving a very
broad overview for now all of these
words will be put in a form of precise
equations later
all right
uh any questions so far
you should feel free to interrupt me at
the endpoint just don't have to raise
your hand in this shop
um
um so but that's not all
uh we'll see that uh for local
vulnerability there also has to be local
operators sometimes referred to as a
field operators
um uh well we're saying what they are
and importantly these field operators
have to obey some important properties
uh including particularly microcontality
now basically uh is a decision of a
technical statement that refers to that
that captures the idea uh that uh
signals cannot propagate faster than the
CPL light in the rapid Theory but in a
precise quantum mechanical setting
all right
um
uh so
um and uh okay uh now uh what is the
inspector field Theory the effective
field Theory
um well it's not really possible for me
to explain in detail without setting up
the some technical tools one effective
field theories are at this point I'll
just say a few things a general some
general facts about it
um it is uh typically
to say typically
uh I like this thank you okay so
typically uh defines
uh only
uh at
the only perturbatively
preservatively
in
some confidence
uh so in contrast because there is which
are there are plenty of examples upon
prepare completely modified as strong
coupling and this effective filter
typically are defined as a form of a
perturbative series without the constant
and it may not have this particularly it
may or may not be convergent
um and uh
it's going to be based on
a path integral a functional integral
over
space and Fields
so you can also use that equal to define
a local fundamental Theory uh but uh
very often
depending on depending on the details of
the theory it may or may not make sense
the numbers are the level uh and also
the effective table theory is that
typically by design it captures a long
distance
um or uh low energy
uh observables uh and not necessarily uh
beyond that
um so uh what are some examples
um
uh any questions about about it yes
uh I will I will describe that uh yeah
so uh let me just say a very roughly uh
uh for a moments that we'll have some
field operators let's say let's call it
uh
which will be associated with based on
point uh let's say it depends on time
for an indeed and concentration X now to
say that you have operator that
Associates by itself is not a very
vehicle statement I can prioritize offer
to however however I want
um now uh there are two key criteria
which I'll write a question later but
I'll just say that now uh that that says
what it means to his office first of all
under concrete transformation if you
move a point to another point in space
time by one query symmetry action
um this correspond unitary operators
just act on this by hand also by moving
it to the by hand at the other point
um but uh also on top of that these
operators have to obey the
microcontality in the sense that you
have a hat at one point in space time
and another Point space time these two
points are space like separated and
constantly disconnected then to
operation commutes so that's kind of the
microcosity these two are the essential
criteria for what it means for the
operator uh to be local so this would be
a concept that's rather alien if you
only know about the underground quantity
times
uh but that will be a central to our
study ability
right uh any other questions
uh all right uh so uh what are some
examples uh let me uh right now some
examples of
uhp versus uh defective Philippi uh that
will some of which will discuss uh in
the squares and not in this course it
will be in the next semester of course
um so
um there's a famous Blackboard Theory uh
this is a uh the theory of a scalar
field who including interaction will
introduce this uh in a few weeks
actually
um but I'm not in a four-dimensional
space time but rather in the B this is
the space line Dimension the capital
whenever capital P I Always mean that
Spare Time Dimension here in the topic
in space so if you construct such a
theory in two or three uh dimension of
metallic space time so either one plus
one the U or two plus one d uh then I
heard that would be a completely fine
numbers
um but uh on the other hand Theory
um is important management
is only sensible only makes sense at the
level of effective field here
all right
um
now um uh some of your favorites uh a
theory that you might want to study are
unfortunately
there are actually not known to be
modified the numbers have been level at
local vulnerability uh neither is the
standard model so all of that belongs to
that
effective field Theory and in fact this
uh might make you a question whether
there exists any local queries at all
the important Dimension uh and uh
surprisingly yes
um but it was not obvious why the theory
is at the point I mentioned are things
like uh Theory
um and uh also uh qcp provides you that
you can have too many flavors of course
um uh and there are other examples uh
although public field theory that arise
with different contexts so so far I
think like DVD or the standard model or
you don't get a theory all arrive in
particular physics the quantum field
theories have much more than
applications that goes far beyond the
particular physics for example we'll see
this is something that
um maybe not so much for this investment
but in the review will be discussed um
model is captured by the uh uh
now in this context I will be talking
about observed quality Institute of
equilibrium so there's no time Evolution
but in fact it will turn out that the
statistical averages
all the good properties
um
there are other examples of effective
field hearing uh some other famous
examples uh there is uh you try to
contact gr okay General activity
technical Theory uh there's also
something called parallel transition
Theory this is
um uh with factors we uh low energy in
fact theories of ions in uh
um uh which is also a famous
um so uh
uh these
uh with five point during q and E uh
we'll discuss this interview a
H and some of these things uh is this
IIT model and unless they're
impoverished Edition Theory this is
uh
yeah it
is very sweet not only will I tell you
the specific models were also developed
in the formula mandatory to understand
um
uh any questions
uh let me just mention that uh you know
they are uh these uh historical terms of
renalizability of vulnerability that
really refers to I would say the
Practical theories uh and uh in a sense
that will not quite discuss in detail
now but we'll come to this later
here these first three examples are
going to be renewalizable uh
indicates anything wrong with uh
okay so that's uh that's a kind of a
sketch of the subjects of study uh any
questions or comments
um so uh now let me uh
uh describe the the plan uh uh all these
lectures
um so it was there so so the plan of
course
um I'm going to uh begin with uh the
more familiar uh subject of just uh
playing oh it's not right division
quantum mechanics with a feel free
though but we're going to study the
quantum mechanics in a language that's
perhaps uh unfamiliar uh in your
undergrad economic tennis course but
will be uh the standard uh tool
technical tool instead of quantum field
Theory so well uh while in your uh
underwater Independence class you
probably learned it in the language of
panintonian uh we're going to be
considering the lagrangian formulation
um
of
one mechanics
uh now we'll come to this in more detail
uh in the next lecture uh but as you uh
probably know in the classical
mechanics uh that uh the lagrangea and
the hamiltonian formulations are uh more
or less equivalent right so you can
define a mechanical system with a it's
like well your action and uh you can
derive the Euler grunge equation which
is equivalent to the extremisation
principle of the action and finally you
write the question of motion uh
alternatively you can describe the
classical state of our system uh in
terms of a pointer face phase captured
by the coordinate momenta uh and then
you can write hamiltonian which invades
of lagrangian biological transformation
and then you have the hamiltonian
equation motion which is equivalent and
presumably usually when you learn this
in classical mechanics you're not very
impressed because these are just trivial
rewriting of one another so why bother
um but in a Quality Mechanical context
uh you probably noticed in the
hamiltonian language where the
hamiltonian
um in one mechanics rather than being a
uh just a
possible function of a coordinate
momentum is promoted to a Quantum
operator the actual filter space whose
eigenvalues the energy spectrum of your
system uh so that's an essential objects
in quantum mechanics which is lagrangia
uh does the end have a prominent role
right in fact it's not even clear
whether the lagrangian is uh and uh you
know rigorously defined or meaningful
performance mechanical system
yeah
okay uh in fact uh the really the only
way I know of which the quantum
mechanics I mean formally through
lagrangian is through the path integral
so spent the time discussing uh half the
growth combination of quantum mechanics
uh and importantly it makes sense of
this topic or we need to encounter the
concept of regularization
which will be very standard in Quantum
field Theory but as we'll see it is
already there in good old is quantum
mechanics with just the beauty which
appeared on
uh that will will discuss uh
perturbation theory in the language
of the passenger
and quantum mechanics uh from which
we'll also derive things such as family
diagrams uh we'll see that if I'm in the
circle appointment diagrams have nothing
to do with conductivity it has
everything to do with the perjury
expansion of the path in the world
and we'll also discuss things such as
the so-called Bruno Foundation
renormalization
and uh
kind of so-called counter terms which as
you'll see
um also have nothing to do with
polynomial Theory and that's everything
to do with a possible formulation of
quantum mechanics
so again these basic concepts of the way
and then uh we'll move to uh detail
Theory so uh
the second part of this the semester
what what not the second part but in a
few weeks we'll discuss
um a relativistic
relativistic uh particles
uh and videos
um so uh we'll discuss things like
scalar build Theory like five four
Theory
uh we'll discuss uh the notion of grid
functions and functional Theory
uh the notion of asymptotic states in a
scattering problem
that this is kind of more a particular
or in physics oriented uh uh Concepts
and we'll discuss uh the so-called
scattering Matrix or S Matrix which is
the central observable of uh uh large
path of quantum field theories uh and
how they're related to the green
function by the stock quality LG
reduction
yeah
um and through that we also will
understand uh why it is that uh the
final diagrams can be used to calculate
scattergics
um and uh then
uh in the uh
the third part of this register
uh search
a big set of topics
um we will
discuss uh particles
uh and uh Appeals
uh with Sid
uh now I would like to always
distinguish the content of 40 bills
because they are really really different
things uh by a field I generally we
generally will meet the local field
operator in this like it's quite hard of
writing and particles are particles it
smells like a particle looks like a
particle will be a particle and the part
of the field are really very different
concepts
um and uh the particle can you spin and
you'll see and the deals can carry spin
but the speed and party on the spin the
field have nothing to do with each other
um and we'll see uh what they mean and
we'll also uh classify
um classification
of The Residency quality folks
but suddenly working the particles
whether there can be will understand why
is it that you can have a steam one half
Fermi Alice and not just being one third
particles for the measures
um and uh and then we'll discuss things
like
um
and uh engagements
and uh and then uh you know there will
be some kind of applications that will
come to at the end of this methods uh
Magnetic Moment of the electron and uh
things like that
okay so so that's the that's the plan
for uh the course as far as the content
is concerned uh any questions
uh the capitalization will be somewhere
here uh what we'll discuss discuss the
combination of the fields in preparation
before setting up a scalar field Theory
uh that was uh uh you know I was uh in
preparing for these lectures I was
debating uh myself whether I want to do
the planning of component behind this
first what was the condition that feels
first I decided to do that first uh uh
just just to get this out of the way and
uh
any other questions
uh it's okay uh but in today's lecture
I'd like to at least give a uh not only
overview but some motivation for uh you
know why why am I going to uh
in fact the first question is
um you know we don't
uh
you know what why do party local
businesses need to know uh build here uh
why why isn't enough to just talk about
particles
that's a very question you should ask
yourself it's not obvious why
um
attempt to explain whether to sell so
the question is uh why
uh do we
need
uh field Theory
uh
to describe
uh the quality mechanics of particles
uh
where uh
investigation
okay this is not obvious
let's try so uh has anyone behind the
system uh from beautiful
um
physical state as the any quantity kind
of a system
um there's a uh probably going to be a
vacuum state
uh let's call it Omega
um
uh and uh
uh we're going to uh assume
um we'll see that this is a reason
something but I want to assume that at
the backing stage is invarian under
Uncle symmetry it's a reasonable
assumption if it's not the area and then
if you perform a the government
transformation or something you get a
different value state so that would be
it sounds unreasonable
um and if in particular one of the
generators of the uh on our symmetry is
a Time translation generator which
hamiltonian so uh
will tell us that the back in the state
should have zero energy
um and on top of that we can have some
particles so let's say let's try so
let's say Minnie would have some single
particle state
uh well it reminiscent particle will be
labeled and you can you can find the
basis for the particle such as this
painting space are labeled by the
spatial momentum uh we can write it back
there for the party so what you say
State my uh convention that
um
uh that I will always write the mikowski
momentum let's say very important
measure the three block one dimension uh
I write in the house again uh for a
momentum energy vector and P mu and uh
it's uh uh time component negative
energy will be okay after zero and then
the special momentum as uh
um as uh
P Vector uh now uh unless as stated
otherwise I'm generally going to work in
arbitrary is based on Dimension uh so mu
it will be zero one two and B
you know as a you know if you're part of
your business you might wonder why would
I care about it before uh well uh here
is a example of the study the typing
models
actual
describes some actual uh object uh solid
dimensions
uh so I'm going to repeat this space 9d
to be General but often you can for now
you can think of equal three uh sorry uh
D will be able to create and dimensions
so it's Omega goes from zero to Ability
minus one
um and uh so uh if you have a randomized
particle it's typically is going to have
a definite Mass uh and uh and you
probably know the energy of the particle
dispersion relation
Theory
so uh if the vacuum energy is zero
then the
uh the hamiltonian one particle states
that is about to give you for the
particle of death in the momentum
definitely special momentum is about to
give you the energy which is a service
Elsewhere for some M which is a mass of
the particle
okay
okay any questions about this
okay so so far uh nothing you know no
big deal now uh you can also Imagine
multi-particle States
multiple States so let's imagine we have
a end party mistake and sitting and
party posts enabled by a spreading
movement that D1 they do all the way to
the end
uh they could be identical particles
uh and uh I'm going to uh assume for now
that the particles are non-interactive
so you can say a very simple system of
uh where uh a physical system where or
Hillary space okay you know consists of
states that they have Aboriginal number
of particles but these particles are not
interacting let's say they all have the
same mass that perhaps The Identical
particles uh so then the hamiltonian
I'm going to act on the state
this
one at the end and uh will this be
um
the energy will just be the sum of
energy of each one of those particles
foreign
States and we have already specified how
the hamiltonian account every single
state uh we're all set we haven't solved
this one kind of system and there's
nothing more to do
yes
I don't really care I've just declared
to say they're there uh all right I mean
the system is not interactive so there's
nothing to do to break but that's that's
my system well well as soon as we'll
later study interacting systems and you
can create a part of West Catherine but
I don't have to say how I created the
state exists now that's the system I'm
going to study for the moment it's a
very simple question
um and other questions yeah
and uh you're always a lot to consider
in a true position of the states but
when I say night interrupting I just
mean that the energy of any particular
state in the sum of energy of these
particles there's no potential
contributions to any digital
interactions so
um
maybe it depends on you know
[Music]
maybe a rather boring one but the reason
I'm talking about this is just to
explain that you can easily construct a
runability variant on the kind of a
system without ever talking about Fields
now here it is
there's a question about
you know uh careers how to create the
particles
um I said you know that's not something
I need to discuss but we can uh if you
if you wish Define a public operation in
a national operators in the following
way at this point so so we can we can
introduce
introduce uh
uh article
uh creation
and uh
annihilation
operators
usually call these uh a dagger and a uh
which are going to be also labeled by
the momentum of the particle of the
degrades
the idea I'm going to write it as a
subscript P Vector note that to specify
the moment of the particle I just need
to specify the expression length and the
energy is always in this case determined
me by the by the this characterization
so I don't have to say in addition when
the energy is
um
um so uh so I'm going to uh divine
the question operator uh by how they act
on these states well the way that you
can Define that is more or less obvious
so for example the one particle say
should be the equation operator uh AP
Vector under the vacuum
and uh I would like to say that maybe
that's a particle States you want an
accurately
you just act two of these vibration
operators
uh on the back
uh and uh and and so forth
uh now I haven't so far uh specified the
normalization of this basis of
multiplying for States and then specify
that now uh uh it's important to for me
to specify the computation relation of
the A and A9 so by the way of course I
should have said that these collected
operators
uh and uh and then I have to tell you
the competition relation of this
equation and international operators for
example populations
as
um uh there should be a non-trivial
computation relation between uh the
margin operator and the conversion
operator so we do AP and AP Prime and
Dagger
um this uh should be uh and then zero
only if we uh particle momenta coincide
and so here let me uh choose the
analyzer you can mentioned so this is
the Delta function so Delta we're in B
plus B minus one it's greater Dimensions
so Delta of T minus one of the P Vector
minus
as you can see if I
uh basically overlap this is C and P
Prime the one particle in one part of
the same with certain momentum P Prime
that I can write as uh so so this guy
here is uh an A B Prime
a dagger in the vacuum and that guy
there is a vacuum raw uh actually with
the the
commission conjugate of uh which is a a
uh and uh and then I use the
conversation I have to use this a and I
like that I can replace
so the result of this is
so so I'm not just saying that I'm
choosing a normalization for my one
particle State and such that the overlap
between one particle said another one
part of the state is yes
so why did that sometimes like
in in some places I've seen this
um Delta function has two pieces
that this is their matter of a new
military convention right I'm I'm free
to rescale uh a and a dragon by factor
of two and I would just change my
opinion convention because two now you
see um there's one part of the state
correspond to a plant wave of the
particle uh should be speaking is not a
globalizable stage anyway
um if you want to perform an organizable
say you had to take away package for
example you can take some safe side that
is
um you know it integrated by this
against a function
the overall
constant
or you know or non-constant the overall
factor is another connection I'm allowed
to for example I can also rescale this
sap by a factor of the energy
one-third power or whatever it does not
matching my recommendation but once I
fixed
um
any other questions
yeah
each state uh no the license operator
should reduce the partial number by what
just like a question after an increase
in particular number by one so the
vacuum has a zero particles and
that that's a sort of the definition of
part of the definition
any other questions
yes but we also agreed to choose the
energy of the vacuum State however we
want or uh right so that's a good
question uh I stated this as following
from our assumption that the vacuum is
concurring bearings now of course you uh
you know you could trivially redefine
your hamiltonian by adding to it a
constant uh you're you're allowed to do
that uh but uh uh I'm going to uh assume
that uh that I introduce this to be two
zero it's uh it's a natural a soundtrack
because
um we would like to see that there is a
unique
um but not even necessary unique would I
would assume that this vacuum state is
symmetry and we'll see shortly
in a bit that this H is one of the
generators of our Symmetry and to say
the state between variants and the
Symmetry Visa or the general suitable
analysis as in any uh
continuous level symmetry requirements
uh any other questions
all right uh so uh given this uh this
equipment and actually operators well
why do I do this well uh we can then uh
Express the hamiltonian and directly in
terms of these uh creation International
operations without having able to say
how the acts on the basis of States uh
so you can easily verify that in fact in
terms of this in terms of this
in terms
of uh daggers they can write a
hamiltonian as uh integral
times uh AP uh dagger KD
the attack is
the occupation number uh for the
particles so you can I'll let you verify
for itself using the commutative
relation that this hamiltonian
background is the definition but produce
the expected uh enter which is different
energy
arguments
that's much less obvious we'll see that
there are masses particles oh they're
almost much harder in the real world and
we can also study that we call as
vulnerable Theory
um and for Math and particles it's not
actually obvious why you want to demand
the number of particles have to be
financed and that is actually a very
subtle question
um we may not even be able to get to it
this semester but it's definitely tied
to the issue of infrared Divergence uh
in uh into a different instance
okay
um uh any other questions
uh all right
so
so here it is we have uh this is one
kind of assistant will have you find
this situation and that's an operators
everything on the hamiltonian uh and uh
By Design This is a quantity chemical
system uh of uh free
very relative interesting
this thing
[Music]
so if you're just interested in
describing quantity mechanics are free
line free in the sense of that they're
not interacting with one another
um but then we're done
and so so then you don't have to take
this course you can go home uh but uh
uh but the thing is uh we like to be
able to describe interactions so what
about
what about uh
uh Interactive
interactive particles
uh well uh you might say that oh that's
uh that's not a big deal uh so uh you
know I can I can think so let's call
this
page uh let's call this patient zero
what are the three Theory
um so a lot of important mechanics we
can just be whatever provision operative
we would like so you can add some
interaction terms
and let's try that okay so uh for
example you might even include uh
interaction terms and hamiltonian that
allow uh changing particle numbers so
for example you can have a uh let's go
contain operatives like a dag or a
dagger a where they have some numerical
assignments
so sorry I uh let's say like this or or
a uh dagger a a so this this guy for
example uh you can take this actually
one particle States it's a and I the one
particle you can create two particles so
this operator would act on the
supermarket State and give you one part
of the states this internal kind of
interaction will change the number of
particles
okay
um
so so okay so we can do that so what's
the big deal
um
uh
the issue is the following so in
principle you could have you could have
done that
um but it's actually quite difficult to
introduce interactions in this manner uh
in a way that preserves the relativistic
symmetry okay so
um so
so the issue
is that it is uh possible but not easy
not easy
to find
age interaction
that
respects
uh
realistic symmetry
uh why is that
um
why I say that
the the issue is quite valid
uh
okay so uh let me draw a schematic
picture of uh space and time a space by
some social coordinate X Factor and uh
time
um
so
um if we have some uh
event or some disturbance of the system
that occur at uh at one point is based
on say at Time Zero it's on location
States let's say here's the light column
uh the library travels in this in this
picture I'm okay I'm only drawing one
special direction right so
um
I'm also working in units where spli is
equal to one uh so the the light
we're travel around a raise of 45 degree
angle left and right and
a introductory like this would be a time
like uh we would correspond the
propagation signal uh slower than the
speed of light where it's a trick like
this
uh outside of the light column would be
uh would be a super luminal and that's
not supposed to be allowed in a regular
Theory so so scooper let me know
uh
propagation
should be opinion
so I'm not allowed to to say that I can
you know disturb the system here there's
a great important here and have some
measure some response at that point in
this space-time that's not impossible if
I if I disturb the system over here I
should only have response within a byte
that's a that's just a constraint from a
retrovista causality and any recognition
Theory uh should have this property
uh but you see this kind of property is
not built-in in the form of the Hamilton
information
nothing tells you the the speed limit uh
you know the influence will be uh April
right instant dates
um
so uh uh it's uh you have to you know in
fact
this is not very
easy exercise but you can try you're
welcome to I'm trying to conclude some
interactive charm and see if you can
arrange them to be such that uh the
probability of signal such that there
will be no super aluminum population of
signal and that's actually not in
YouTube so image
um but uh let me uh uh and let me
quantify this a bit uh better in the
language of these local uh
field operators
so
so in order to actually describe this
kind of a local
disturbance of the system in uh in a way
that is mathematically meaningful
um
so in a optimistic
uh Quantum Mechanicals system
we might expect uh sort of the local
disturbance
and so you you change your system at
some point
by the state by some operation localized
at the point in space at the instant in
time uh you will you might expect that
there's a local disturbance uh to be
uh represented
uh by some kind of field
operator
and then when I say that the word field
uh what does it mean all I mean
is that operate depends on some
space-time Point thanks
um so
so that is to say
um
uh we have some
operator uh this operator in the usual
Center one mechanics the new operator
act on the filter space and we continue
to be her Mission if you wish and you
know it's expecting value is supposed to
be some physical observed zero sense
um but unlike the uh your perhaps your
we are familiar with uh what we have
here is actually a entire family of
operators labeled by some parameter so I
should emphasize that in my notation
here
um unlike uh probably you are
underground quantum mechanics course
where XMP are operators here when I
write X in this context they're just
parameters they're not operators The
Operators the Spy hat
all right so this x uh mu which is Some
Space Nine uh pointed by the time x0 and
the switch of coordinate X vector this
is just a label this is just a label a
space-time space-time Point
um
and uh I want to say that associated
with that spacing point there is some
operator uh five hats that represents a
disturbance of a system
uh
any questions so far
uh here uh that um now this field
operator uh should obey some uh
properties uh so first first of all I I
said this in words uh early on but let
me say this more precisely
um so if I look at if I had
and if I had at the
different point x Prime
uh so these two operators are supposed
to be related
uh by
uh Hungary symmetry
uh the the ascends next to the center X
to X Prime
so you know given two SpaceTime points
and because again uh space time I can
always find some uh Hungary symmetry
this could be just translation it could
be different learning transformation
whatever
um uh of course it's highly not unique
um that takes X to X Prime uh and uh you
would expect if you have a symmetry that
takes x with X Prime uh this symmetry uh
acting on uh by hat an X that should
take Pi hat of X so if I had of X Prime
that that's a uh that's a reasonable
requirement if you want to say that this
far has indeed tied to that space-time
point in some sense
um so uh to probably buy this
I don't actually
write something meaningful
um so suppose so consider
um
uh transformation
uh that takes X mu is on X Prime U which
we said is uh consists of um
transformation
and like this
and a translation
in mu so you can shift X by some
constants
uh straight line Vector that translation
symmetry
so this is a translation
and you can also either rotate or boost
under which is Lawrence transformation
and as you might recall uh
transformation matrix and the review is
supposed to preserve the orientation
penetration so uh performance
Matrix
I'm using here I'm mostly positive
conventional signature for the likelsia
metric
um any questions about this
that's just the usual uh when we write
the bunker transformation in special
relativity
um
so
um now uh probably your freshman
mechanics class you learn this bunker
asymmetry at the transformation of
space-time points but then in quantum
mechanics you learn the Symmetry is
supposed to be represented by unitary
operator uh so uh here we're doing
quantum mechanics so this fun query
symmetry should also be represented by
an actual operator so the Symmetry is
always on a state of hubris how does
this symmetry act on the state in
Hillary space uh well
um so in symmetry
symmetry
uh
is represented
uh by
a unitary
operator
uh I'll call it you
uh if it does in some way
um Lambda and this is
transformation they will buy this learn
transformation matrix Lambda and the
translation Symmetry by the amount a so
that symmetry will be realized by some
unitary operator U the actor on the
hillbrow space
uh and uh
in particularly
you the Symmetry is supposed to act um
operator so so
mistakes the state get transformed by
you back in the States but if I have an
operator uh if only you can use the the
operator gets transformed by uh
conjugation uh by a similarity
transformation with that obligatory
operator so for example
um
the operator to U and the a
uh U inverse
so that's a similar transform operator
and our requirement is activity
transform operator should be equal to
the field Operator by hand at the new
Point Lambda X plus a I'm using the
shorthand notation as a decision
indices are implicit as in the
expression
okay so so that's the statement that uh
Pi has at X and if I had X Prime X Prime
are related by the symmetry
uh any questions so far
uh we will consider that later on for
here for now in fact uh uh
that's very good point I'm assuming that
this is a scalar field operator uh now
in fact any uh probability with a large
class of many different kinds of scalar
offers you always have scalar I should
say that uh we uh you know the the field
operator whether it's good or not has
nothing to do with what kind of
particles we have in this here you can
have a theory with uh permians or
against bosons where you can still have
a scalar active operatives
any other questions
uh very good uh so uh okay uh now what
do we know about uh you learn the age
well um uh so far I haven't told you
much I just said that there should be
something to operate dependent amount of
a but exactly how uh well
um
uh one way to to study uh continue
symmetry is to view
um any kind of a finite
semi-transformation that's composed of
implemented intestinal Transformations
and development convenient to begin by
studying the different decimal version
of the symmetry so
um in fact in this case it's the Titus
to focus on that but unless I just
consider that
that's the model
version
of this where you can take a Lambda new
new to be uh
postal identity transformation plus a
small modification
Omega
uh and uh a is automatically smallest of
solid epsilence because it's small
um and uh
this this Omega you can verify for
yourself but uh
but for example uh this condition that
wrote there uh if you plug in a land
that should be a chronic or Delta plus
Omega then if it decimal if you spend
the first order in comics you'll find
that
Omega lowercase mu Nu where an end
system is defined by lowering with the
economy
is uh anti-symmetric
symmetric
uh with respect to
exchanging I mean
lower the index window
in this way
um
it's probably something that I've seen
in the context of the circular antibody
anyways
um so uh for the infinitesimal uh
Hungary transformation uh this U is user
operator will be very close to Identity
in fact we can expand to first order uh
in these parameters
Omega and Epsilon has a identity
operator uh plus some anti-commissions
operator as always a user operator who
is also identical you can write it as
one was an information operator and
there's actually original operator can
be written in the following form
um already that's there's a term
proportional to optional meaning
and then there's a thing that multiplies
uh Omega renew I said is
the lower instances isometric I think
the fact that one half here if I
mentioned and uh one person J hats video
so this is just a definition uh I'm uh
uh well all I'm saying here is that for
it's a decimal concrete transformation
the associated symmetry unitary operator
can be expanded as identity identity
operators plus an anti-permission
operator if I pull out the background I
then the C hat and the J hats these are
going to be permission operators
uh any questions about this
operator is what
uh oh I'm assuming that the
filtering
uh operator
so it's you do that you're worried about
the Thanksgiving
yeah
this if it's one thought something in
business decimal thing has to be
independent
uh so both so
so I'm considering the case that these
are small uh and uh so we'll get to an
extent uh to uh first order
uh this will ultimately be be sufficient
for our discussion because I can recover
the finite form by control box
all right
um okay so I can only do this
uh any questions so far
uh now yes so
when you what you wrote here is just the
general form for
okay
yeah
they are they have some names so this
device they have some name that we had
is the so-called energy momentum
operator
um and the J hat is uh
the operator correspond to the Lawrence
boost
and the angular momentum
uh so uh indeed uh the client is going
to be that uh the for example uh if I
um so uh you have to be careful with
raising and lowering illnesses of
therapy proper view which is
um now I'm not going to
um
derive
uh right the commutators
uh the communicators of these and J's
um using
the property that is used as a compose
upon the rule of concrete transformation
in particular you uh Lambda
hey
uh let's say Lambda prime a prime
Consulting with u Lambda a
well this sends X2 Lambda X plus a and
this one does it again with Lambda Prime
X Prime let's have a vehicle to U of uh
Lambda Prime Lambda multiplying it
matrices and here you have a prime a but
that's a prime uh I will let you think
for yourself how to derive from this
combination relations of the P10 J it's
by the point that they all dictated by
the requirement that is used they want
to have an interpretation as the user
operators that generates conquering so
correspondence is actually
although
um
uh uh wow this is the legal statement
that the energy momentum are the uh
charges the conserve charges are
self-defense asymmetry in time and space
um we will give a more systematic
discussion of the context of field
Theory uh using the author procedure uh
in a few elections
um uh but it's by the way uh I posted a
suggested reading on the uh um on the
slack Channel if you want to uh you're
going to read more about this uh it's
all in scattered in various sections in
new member in glory detail
um the discussion of the
procedure which will come to a little
bit later
um which will allow you to express this
these and the JS in terms of spatial
integrals of the stress energy tensor
um
you understand exactly how these are
required related to the uh Not Just
Energy sensor
um that you can read about in uh chapter
welcome to this uh welcome to this later
but this is the general fact of any
economic panelist
yes so
just trying to check how you is to
encourage if you try and multiply advice
uh well uh if you have one uh uh plus I
of some uh permission operator
and stagger
[Music]
thank you
any other questions
um all right uh
so um the point of this little
discussion is just to explain what it
means that for my heart to be tied to
space-time point x let me just reiterate
it's really this this equation here that
says the bunkery Symmetry uh uh
transformation which is realized by the
unitary operator oh you should act on
five I say that you by U inverse is the
spy and the the transformed space-time
points
okay that that's that and uh but then uh
I so far I haven't said anything about
uh without it uh so that's that's going
to be the key so uh a key property is
going to be
um
is going to be micro product
micro
sology
uh that in this particular example is
going to say that we're going to demand
find half of the X and if I had a y
where X and Y are to space uh whenever
whenever uh X and Y are uh space like
separated
that is
and you always want to use the
convention x minus y squared this is the
Laurentian inner product support the
calcium space A Space Nine this is
defined to be minus of X zero minus y
zero the time difference plus the
spatial difference X Factor minus y is
squared
um so I.E this is a
found him
I said okay uh of course I as I said I'm
always pointing that unit still alive is
that the one
okay
um so so that that's my book before that
yeah at least apply to this uh this
local field Operator by hand uh we're
talking about here
uh any questions so far
no it's um uh not obvious at the moment
but we're back at the requirement of the
existence of operative if I had tied to
a special point x in that way elevated
through that it's an academic constraint
on the quantum system uh in fact you can
ask
um
Okay so
you can ask uh but just apply to our
system of three particles
uh intuitively it should because we have
nine interacting particles and the
particles themselves the propagation are
very basic dispersion relation so the
system must be quasim
um but uh can you actually write down
this local field operators in that uh in
that theory so
uh yeah what about
about
our model the very simple model of uh
companion model of a free uh relative
District
particles
um so for example if that is now already
right I'm worried about the hamiltonian
which is uh
integral expression momentum P lacker of
sorry the p square plus M squared
ap.gov ID
you can also write the momentum hat to
emphasize this operator we also write
the the capital P momentum operator in a
similar way
this will be here
AP
gar AP so I hope you can see the
difference in my handwriting of the
lowercase D which is a integration
variable versus the capital P which is
the operator all right so this is the
expression one item operator but that's
the variable we're integrating and
this if you have the meal directly there
is just the vector of organism H and it
is
um so these are some of the uh
generators uh among our symmetry
generators of this uh this model uh we
can also try to write the J so they're a
little bit more complicated I won't
write that right now it'll become clear
how to construct that later
um but uh the key question you might ask
or the most obvious uh question you
might ask is what the heck is this uh my
hat in this in this model uh does it
even exist
um so just take a couple minutes to to
write down this line
uh so uh
so the question is
does uh if I had an X available all the
nice properties that we just demanded
and doesn't exist in this uh
okay uh the answer is uh yes uh it's not
totally obvious
um we all have different way to
understand this uh later so let me just
write an answer
does exist okay it's run one it's not
unique but here's one uh remember the
of P vector
uh there's some normalization basically
mentioned it's too high not too
important but this is important
Omega T where Omega T is the energy of
positive structural relation
a particle of mass m
and uh with ap here
into the e to the high P starting with x
minus I Omega e minus X naught plus the
on this conjugate the temperature
conjugate a b dagger due to the F minus
I the X Plus
Omega B
and I'm integrating over p uh this Omega
p is just the energy according to
display relation right to inspection
now I will not ex I don't have time to
explain this right now uh uh uh I will
invite you to the the theme on this for
yourself I will give some explanation
next time but we'll we'll understand
this much more symptomatically uh later
um that uh this say you construct it uh
will obey all the nice properties that
will just imagine it's going to be pi to
the X you're going to transform out the
conversation in the right way and
importantly it's going to obey uh
fidelity
um so
some interacting system
um that uh that had similar properties
had this this kind of microcosality
um and that as you see
um would not be very easy in the
hematological problem uh for the basic
reason that the hamiltonian probabilism
is such that it singles our time uh
versus Space it doesn't uh the pancreas
symmetry is not very manifest uh for
example here you know we're all often
writing uh integrals in special momentum
that doesn't look obviously Lawrence
covariance even though the underlying
physics is Lawrence invariance uh we're
not you can always you'll be able to
disrupt
operator but it's not trivial to check
that the system actually has that
symmetry
um so it will be useful to have a
formulation in which the Conqueror
symmetry is Manifest and that cannot be
done through the hamiltonian and that's
why the lagrangian populism will be
useful and next time we'll discuss
um how to formulate quantum mechanics
using the lagrangian language
uh okay any uh final questions before we
end yes
um
is there a way to construct it like
right now
I just put it out of the hat for now yes
because this is only a uh you know kind
of a general motivation
um uh of course this is the correct
answer you can check oh you might check
that it works but we'll explain how to
systematically construct this thing
[Music]
for example
or something like that
um
we will have all the different
properties uh so by looking at the
unique operative
many many operators that have similar
properties
okay so
um
foreign
thank you
um
foreign
thank you foreign
thank you
foreign
the things
America
um
yeah
uh
and uh
like what you can do is like with like
it's all right
for the entire system but just
integrating that all elements
to like low spreader
you like have this free form and then
you use applicability
yeah
a lot of stuff I do for instance
absolutely
um
no problem
thank you